Hey everyone and thanks for jumping back
into the cryptoverse.
Today we're going to talk about Bitcoin
the next 60 days. If you guys like the
content, make sure you subscribe to the
channel, give the video a thumbs up, and
also check out the sale on into the
cryptoverse premium at into the
cryptoverse.com
where you can more closely follow along
with the charts that we're going to be
discussing in this video. As a reminder,
make sure you guys get your ticket for
the ITC conference that's taking place
in late November. Get your ticket before
September 1st as prices will go up then.
Bitcoin is currently trading at around
$63,000.
And in this video, I want to talk about
why I think the next 60 days are fairly
important for determining how this bare
market plays out and and what what
eventually happens to hopefully push us
into the next phase of the market cycle.
Now the next 60 days are important
because on average from about mid August
to about midocctober can be a fairly
weak time in markets. If you look at
monthly returns for Bitcoin in midterm
years, you'll see that in 2022, Bitcoin
was red in May and June, green in July,
and then red in August and September. In
2018, it was red in May and June, green
in July, and then again red in August
and September. 2014 was a little
different. It was green in May, but then
red June, July, August, and September.
And so far in 2026, again, red in May
and June, green in July. And the
argument probably is like, well, maybe
August is red and so is September. Now,
there's no guarantee. I would say
seasonality works maybe about 70% of the
time. If you look at all years on
average, Bitcoin is red in August and
September and all the other months on
average are in fact green. If you change
the calculation to just say take it from
2018, then on average there are a couple
of other red months like June can often
be read uh November has been red on
average since 2018, but that's of course
mainly because you had this massive drop
in November of 2018. If you were to
change this to say 2019, you can see
that it just sticks with June, August,
and September. So about mid August to
mid-occtober can be a weaker time in the
market. And you might say, well, right
now, Bitcoin is actually up this month.
But so what, right? Like it it it also
was up at the very beginning of 2022 as
well, uh, or at the very beginning of
August 2022. You can see that Bitcoin
went up in the first week or two of
August 2022 and then it gave those gains
back as we went into midepptember and
really it stayed weak even into
mid-occtober. So the argument is that
there's this window of weakness that has
kind of creeped back up on us. We had
our window of strength briefly in July
and then the question is is well what's
going to happen over the next 60 days
when Bitcoin goes through one of its
historically weakest periods in midterm
years again on average going back all
years if you go all the way back to 20
2010 and you look at midterm years on
average Bitcoin drops about 10 to 11% in
August and it drops about 8% in
September. So that's not a small drop,
right? I mean 10% down um from the
current prices would you know and if you
take another 8% below that but say 10%
down will put Bitcoin at at 56k or so 8%
below that you know puts you in the low
50s. So the question is is like is this
the future that Bitcoin has? Now,
the next 60 days are crucial, not just
because that's when the main window of
weakness occurs, but also it lines up
with the ROI from the low of Bitcoin. If
you look at the ROI from the low to the
high, you can see that the last three
cycles topped out relatively close
together. This cycle topped on
approximately day 1,50.
Last cycle topped on day 1,059.
The cycle before that topped on day
about 1,068.
So in fact
two cycles ago to last cycle it it was 9
days less and then this past cycle to or
the two cycles ago to the last cycle it
was another nine days less. So it's like
where the market participants are front
running it by about a week and a half,
right? Because they don't want to they
learned their mistakes in the last cycle
and they don't want to learn it again.
So you can see that Bitcoin topped out
when it always topped out. Now if you
extend this to the low, what you'll see
is that two cycles ago we bottomed out
on day 1432.
Last cycle we bottomed on day 1436. So
it took four more days. We're currently
on day 1360.
So, in 60 days,
we're going to be on day 1420,
which is within a week or two of when
prior market cycle lows occurred. And
remember this timing just coincidentally
or maybe not coincidentally
happens to align
with historically one of the weakest
times for Bitcoin which is August and
September. Now here's the thing. Here's
the thing from a structural perspective.
We have made the comparison between this
cycle and 2018 a lot. Right? Right. And
and there's a lot of reasons to compare
it. You could say that structurally it's
the same thing, right? The only
difference is that we topped on Euphoria
back in 2017 and we topped on apathy
now. But look at this. I mean, you have
a low in February at 6,000, a higher low
in late March, early April, and then a
lower low in the summer. It's the same
thing this time, just 10x higher. You
set your low in February of 2026. You
put your higher low in late March, early
April. You sweep the low in the summer.
the difference. We're holding at 60K
rather than 6K back in 2018. Same
presidents in office. We're just 10x
higher. Okay, that's the only only real
difference. And then also, of course,
the other difference, I suppose, is that
uh we topped on euphoria back then,
whereas this time there was it was more
of an apathetic top. If Bitcoin had had
this type of blowoff top in 2025 like it
did in 2017, then you might have had
that rotation into higher risk assets
into all coins. But we didn't have that.
And so because the apathetic top
occurred, there was no rotation. But the
structure of the bare market looks
remarkably similar. And if you look at
the year-to- date ROI of Bitcoin in 2026
and overlay it with 2018, you can see
that 2026 is kind of like a less
volatile version of 2018. And maybe it's
a less volatile version of 2018 because
we didn't have as many retail
participants panic selling at the top or
sorry, panic buying at the top, I should
say.
Because remember when you look at social
interest of Bitcoin this cycle it's
nowhere near what it was at the end of
2017. You can see that right now social
risk is about 0.2 2018 social risk in
October about 0.2. In 2022 social risk
in in or sorry in August was uh August
of 2020 2018 it was about 0.2 August of
2022 was about.5. So this bare market
from a social interest perspective is
more like 2018 than it is 2022.
We just got to this social interest in a
very different manner, right? A very
different route to get to this area, but
we find ourselves at the same place,
right? Like had Bitcoin gone to 200K and
we had a rotation into altcoins like we
did in 2017 when we went to 20K, we
still might have find ourselves at the
exact same price today. is the point I'm
trying to make. Now, where it gets
interesting is that you have the weakest
time in midterm years on average, August
and September, which is where we are in
now. Again, yes, you could say, well,
technically we're up so far in August.
So, what in 2022 in the first week or
two, we also were up and then we still
gave it away. So, the weakest time in
midterm years is kind of around that
August September time frame in terms of
setting new lows or at least kind of
retesting the prior lows. that happens
to correspond to the ROI from the low
lining up approximately to mid to late
October. That's why the next 60 days are
crucial.
Now, here's the thing, and this is why
we can't marry one narrative too much.
And again, if if you want if you don't
like this stuff and and you want to join
the mental gymnastics club, they meet
every day on Twitter. There's Twitter
spaces they meet every day and they talk
about the mental gymnastics. So go check
that out. But
extrapolation is dangerous. If you're an
engineer, they'll tell you, right?
Interpolation is okay. Interpolation.
Extrapolation,
don't get comfortable doing that because
if you do, you're probably going to lose
your job. But this is not engineering.
This is dubious speculation in the
cryptoverse.
If you look at when Bitcoin bottomed
three cycles ago,
January, not even in the midterm year,
it was January. By the way, on some
exchanges back then, we didn't actually
bottom until August. I know we don't
really talk about that much, but if you
look at this wick in January 2015, it
was 166, but in August of 2015, we
actually went to 162 on some of these
exchanges. So,
it did last a little bit longer back
then. But here's the thing. That cycle,
let's just say January. The August low
was more of a recession low, not like a
four-ear cycle low. Just like in the
last cycle, the four-year cycle low or
sorry, two cycles ago, the four-ear
cycle low was December, but we also had
another low when the pandemic occurred.
And some some things put in new lows,
like the stock market put in new lows
below the 2018 low. So, you can go lower
than your four-ear cycle low, but you
need some type of like global recession
to cause it. 2015,
we had a recession scare at the end of
2015. In fact, if you were to overlay
the S&P 500 onto the chart, you'll see
the S&P was also struggling in late
2015, which kind of accompanied Bitcoin
down to retesting those lows. Okay. So,
let's just say January.
The next one was December.
The next one was November. So, what
you'll see is that this is becoming
earlier in time from January to
December, December to November. Maybe
the next one is October, right? Doesn't
doesn't have to be, but again, October
is a candidate month. And I would say
the odds of the low being in October are
probably equivalent to the odds of the
low being in every other month combined,
right? So maybe it's like 50% likelihood
of October, but also 50% likelihood that
it could be either, you know, in
combined like July, August, September,
November, December, January or something
like that, right? So October is a
candidate month not only because the ROI
from the low would line up towards then
but also because you can see that every
cycle the low was occurring about one
month sooner in the cycle
in the calendar year.
But there's this thing that we have to
think about and that's the fact that
last cycle
was a November top to a November low.
The cycle before that was a December top
to a December low. So, it's not like
that crazy to be like, "All right, what
about an October top to an October low?"
Back when I mentioned this nearly a year
ago,
some people didn't believe it, right?
They didn't believe we were in a bare
market. But the people that did believe
we were in a bare market or going into
one were like, "That makes sense, right?
About a year, it just makes sense." But
throughout the entire year, because
people have this in their mind like,
"Okay, October, October, October." Every
single time we get any type of a rally,
everyone's like, "Oh, well, you know,
what about the guys waiting for the
October low?" First of all, you I don't
think it makes sense to wait and try to
time the market. I think DCA in the
second half of the midterm year is just
simply the way to go. It's a lot less
stressful. You don't have to worry about
timing the exact bottom. But that's the
narrative that gets put out there is
that like every time there's a rally,
whether it was from 80K back to 98K or
the rally from 60K back up to 83 or the
rally from, you know, 57 or 58 back up
to the to the mid to upper 60s every
single time. The general narrative that
you'll see is that, oh, you know, poor
guys waiting for the October low. That's
why it's hard to like want to put out
too many predictions because people just
ridicule the prediction the entire year.
Even if it ends up coming true or not,
it doesn't really matter. It's easy to
ridicule it for the permabil
cheerleaders, right? You just you
ridicule anyone that's not blindly
bullish. So, you can see that last bare
market 54 weeks, bare market before that
52 weeks.
the 2019 bare market, which again
there's reasons to look at, 37 weeks,
but we had price-based capitulation due
to the pandemic, which arguably sped it
up. The bare market before that one
though
was a little longer, 59 weeks. So you
can see that like it makes sense in my
mind to just look at about this
year-long bare market and say look
there's a reasonable chance it lasts
about a year. 54 weeks from the top
would put you in the week of October
19th. 52 weeks would put you in the week
of October 5th. So it depends on you
know is it more like 2022? Is it more
like 2018?
But there's one consideration to make
here that we haven't really fully made.
When you look at the year-to- date ROI,
you can see that Bitcoin's lows have
been align aligning generally. Well,
but if that's the case, then it means
the drop doesn't occur until November,
right? Like what if what if Bitcoin just
goes sideways for the next three months
like it did in 2018? Like in 2018,
Bitcoin rallied up to the bare market
resistance band in July.
It came back down in mid August and then
rallied again and then came back down
and then just didn't do anything for two
months.
So the next 60 days are instrumental
because if Bitcoin were to take out the
low from June July, if it were to take
out that low into that window of
weakness, then the ROI from the low
chart would line up with the monthly
returns chart
and it would just all kind of line up.
Even the chart that when you look at
presidential returns as measured from
inauguration day would also
coincidentally line up. Maybe not
coincidentally I mean it's all you know
more or less the same thing. But when
you look at returns presidential return
paths for Bitcoin
and we load that on there and you look
at Trump's uh second term compared to
Biden. Look where we are. same price
relative to the to the inauguration day
price. This is exactly where we were
back in 2022 as measured from
inauguration day
and then you can see that it took a
couple more months and then we got the
breakdown and then we were back in
business. So the next 60 days are
instrumental. But what if
it does like what if volatility dies out
and we don't go up, we also don't go
down. Like if it's if it's like 2018, in
that case, the market just didn't do
anything in August, September, and
October. And then just when people
thought the coast was clear,
the floor fell out. So I have to have
that on my radar as well.
because I know that if if it doesn't
happen before the end of October, that
doesn't necessarily mean we're in the
all clear because we've already seen one
bare market in a midterm year that
actually lasted 59 weeks. And if you
were to take this bare market and say,
well, what happens if it lasts 59 weeks?
That would actually put you in like late
November,
right? right? It would put you the week
of November 23rd.
So, when I was thinking about that, I
was and when I was trying to figure out
like when would it make sense to do this
Bitcoin conference um or doing this
conference? We're going to talk about
Bitcoin. We're also talk about other
things like, you know, commodities and
stocks, but when would it make sense to
do it? Obviously, Bitcoin will be a
major theme. I was like, I really want
the low to either be in or be very close
to being in. And you can see that 59
weeks from the top is the week of
November 23rd.
Guess when the conference is
November 21st.
So this is the mindset, right? Don't
marry a specific date. The low could
absolutely be October.
If
August and September end up being weak
and we go below 60K,
if we don't and we kind of hold 60K
begrudgingly,
then yeah, maybe maybe you have to be a
little bit more open-minded as to when
it would occur. But I still think that
October has to be a candidate month. The
other thing that makes me think we're a
little bit ahead of 2018 in terms of
volatility dying off is that in July, we
actually rallied all the way back up to
the bare market resistance band.
But this time we couldn't even be
bothered to get there. Maybe we get
there but couldn't even be bothered to
do it in July. Right in 2018 Bitcoin
rallied up significantly in July, you
know? I mean from the from the June July
low about 50% rally from this low
16%. Not even 20%. So,
if there's just not as many people, you
know, it it it might not take as long
for this to play out.
But those are my thoughts. I would say
the odds the the low for Bitcoin based
on the four-year cycle low, the odds are
that it occurs between like late
September and and and like mid December.
That's that's probably when like I would
say there's a good chance it occurs in
that window. Doesn't mean it can't be
January. Doesn't mean it can't be August
or July, but that's when I would
consider that main window to be. And
then the question is when exactly. And I
think the next 60 days will help us
determine
is it more likely to be, you know,
October? Could it go into November? It's
going to depend on on how it evolves
from here. Do the onchain indicators get
reset, right? Does the MVRVZ score reset
below zero? Because it it tends to do
that in midterm years. Does that reset?
Does the onchain risk that we have that
incorporates not only the MBRVZ score,
but also the PEL multiple, the MBRV
score, the transaction fees, terminal
price, minor cap to thermocap ratio,
market cap to thermal cap ratio. Does
that reset below 0.1 like it normally
does near the end of midterm years? And
so because August and September on
average are weak for Bitcoin,
the next 60 days are really important.
If price goes sideways at 60K like it
did in 2018, then you could kick the can
to November. It's not impossible for
this to go on longer. But I would say
until that happens, I'm going to stick
with approximately a one-year bare
market. October to October makes the
most amount of sense to me. If the
market gives us to reason to pivot, I'll
pivot. But I'm not as interested in
joining the mental gymnastics club in
the meantime. But I absolutely will
pivot if I have the reason to do so. So
those are my views. That's what I think
is why that's why I think it's the next
60 days are very important to Bitcoin.
If you guys like the content, subscribe,
give the video a thumbs up. Again, check
out the sale on into the cryptoverse
premium if you want to follow along a
little bit closer to this cycle uh cycle
behavior for Bitcoin as well as many
other markets. And then also make sure
you guys get your ticket. We'd love to
see you guys uh down in Miami November
20th through the 22nd at the ITC
conference. Tickets are going out
September 1st. Thank you guys for tuning
in and I'll see you next time. Bye.